Curriculum Vitae

Dr. Rebecca Smethurst University of Nottingham University Park NG7 2RD United Kingdom

Email: rebecca.smethurst@nottingham.ac.uk Web: rebeccasmethurst.co.uk

Phone: (+44) 0115 846 8819

I am the Ogden Trust Sixty Symbols research fellow at the University of Nottingham. My research focuses on star formation quenching in galaxies of different morphologies due to supermassive black holes. I am a member of the Galaxy Zoo science team and the .Astronomy conference series "brain trust". I am also an enthusiastic science communicator and regularly present physics interest videos on the Sixty Symbols and Deep Sky Videos YouTube channels.

Research Experience

January 2017 - present

Sixty Symbols Research Fellow: Galaxy Evolution: Inside-out or Outside-In?

University of Nottingham

October 2013 - December 2017:

DPhil Project: The influence of morphology, AGN and environment on the quenching histories of galaxies.

Supervisor: Chris Lintott University of Oxford

October 2011 - June 2012:

MPhys Project: Searching for TP-AGB star signatures in post-starburst ('E+A') galaxies: Are high redshift

galaxy masses over estimated?

Supervisors: Russell J. Smith, John Lucey

Durham University

Observing Experience

October 2017:

Remote observer with the Shane-3m at the Lick Observatory, California

February 2015:

Observer at the CSO in Mauna Kea, Hawaii

November 2014:

Remote observer with the CSO in Mauna Kea, Hawaii

May 2014:

Observer at the INT in La Palma, Canary Islands

Conference Organisation

SOC member for .Astronomy 9, Cape Town, SA

November 2017

SOC member of Galaxy Zoo Tenth Anniversary Conference, Oxford

July 2017

Head of SOC and LOC for .Astronomy 8, Oxford

As lead organiser of .Astronomy 8 in June 2016 I brought together an international community of researchers, educators and communicators to showcase and build upon web-based projects, from outreach and education, to research tools and data analysis. The conference aim was to prepare the community for the future, including the influx of large data sets, innovative data visualisations and the citizen science revolution.

Recent Research Presentations

RAS National Astronomy Meeting

July 2017, July 2016, July 2015

Talk at the Galaxy Morphometrics conference, Leiden September 2016

Talk at the Hidden Monsters conference, Dartmouth

August 2016

Talk at the Galaxy Pathways conference, Santa Catalina Island

August 2016

Seminar at the Institute of Astronomy, Cambridge

July 2016

Seminar at the University of California San Diego

April 2016

Thesis talk at the American Astronomical Society meeting #227

January 2016

Colloquium at the University of Melbourne

November 2015

Achievements & Awards

IoP Early Career Physics Communicators Award 2015

Finalist

FameLab UK National Final April 2014

Audience Winner and Judges Runner-Up

Prize for Achievement in Physics 2008

Bolton School Girls' Division

Parent's Association Prize for Leadership 2008

Bolton School Girls' Division

Teaching Experience

January 2014 - June 2016:

Undergraduate Laboratory Demonstrator, University of Oxford

Employment History

January 2017 - present:

Research Fellow, University of Nottingham

September 2012 - August 2013:

Graduate Engineer, Rolls Royce plc

Education

Doctorate of Philosophy, Pembroke College, University of Oxford

October 2013 - January 2017

1st class Master of Physics, St. Aidan's College, University of Durham

October 2008 - June 2012

Bolton School Girls' Division, September 1998 - August 2008

A-Levels: Physics (A), Maths (A), Further Maths (A), Chemistry (A), General Studies (A)

Positions of Responsibilty

November 2014 - June 2015:

Pembroke College, Oxford, MCR Secretary

June 2014 - November 2014:

Pembroke College, Oxford, MCR Social Secretary